Tatyana Karlen - Portfolio: www.tatyanakarlen.com

tatyanakarlen@gmail.com (416) 662-6937

Profile

I'm a Toronto-based full-stack developer with a specialization in front-end development. I graduated from General Assembly's Software Engineering Immersive program where I learned computer science fundamentals, software engineering and web development.

Skills

Javascript (ES6) | React | Next.js | Python 3 | Django | Node.js | Express | MongoDB | PostgreSQL | MySQL | CSS3 | Sass | HTML5 | Bootstrap | MUI | Tailwind | Git | Typescript

Experience

AUG 2023 - CURRENT

Nuclear Media - Front-End Developer (Contract)

- Front-end developer at a boutique digital web agency working in an agile projectmanagement style.
- Working in Next.JS running on a headless REST API CMS. Maintaining and expanding various existing Nuclear Media projects.

MAR 2023 - AUG 2023

Freelance, Remote/Toronto - Front-End/Full-Stack Developer

- Design, development and deployment of web applications. Assisted clients with content, SEO, design and marketing for their brand and target markets.
- Worked as a front-end developer/UI designer for a client on a Chat-GPT-powered What's App Chat application utilizing Next.JS, Typescript and Tailwind CSS.

OCT 2022 - MAR 2023

905devshop, Remote/GTA - Intern Front-End/Full-Stack Developer

- Designed and built responsive user-friendly interfaces utilizing Typescript (Javascript) and Chakra UI (CSS library) in Next.js working in an agile team.
- Worked with a relational MySQL database to perform CRUD operations and retrieve data.

General Assembly Bootcamp, Other Projects - Software Engineering Portfolio

<u>Untitled Magazine</u> - MERN-stack content-management system and online magazine built with React, MongoDB, Node.js, Express, Bootstrap. Features AJAX API endpoints, JWT authentication, Cloudinary image storage.

<u>CookBook</u> - Recipe app built with React (Javascript), Spoonacular API, Firebase, Bootstrap. Enables a user to fetch recipes based on search and like/unlike individual recipes stored in a Firebase database.

Spark - Online dating single-page-application built with Next.js, Typescript, MySQL, Prisma and Chakra UI. Allows users to sign-up and be matched with potential mates based on preferences.

<u>Tinterest</u>- Pinterest-style image-sharing app built with Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Materialize CSS, Amazon S3 cloud storage. Allows users to post 'interest' type images and save/like other user's images.

<u>Thriftd</u> - RESTful MEN-stack e-commerce application built with Javascript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Google Oauth 2.0 authentication, Imgur photo API and a no-SQL MongoDB database. Allows logged-in users to post second-hand clothing items for sale and wish list/purchase other user's items.

For demo/code links visit www.tatyanakarlen.com or https://github.com/tatyanakarlen

Education

Software Engineering Immersive Certificate - General Assembly - 3.87 GPA

Diploma in Fashion Arts/Fashion Marketing - Humber College, Toronto

Grade 10 Piano Performance, Advanced Music Theory - Royal Conservatory Of Music

Past Work Experience

MAR 2020 - DEC 2022

Sutton Group Realty Systems Inc, Toronto - Digital Marketing, Wordpress

• Created digital marketing content for web and social media distribution, as well as SEO-friendly custom web pages on Wordpress and Wix.

JAN 2013 - MAR 2022

Alla Breve Academy of Music, Vaughan - Piano and Music Theory teacher